

@

kingsleybotchwayedu11 @gmail.com



+233592960273



Kumasi, Ghana 9808



https://www.linkedin.co m/in/kingsley-botchway-483526116



Bold Profile

WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

 https://github.com/Mhi sterKhing6

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science:
Computer Science
Kwame Nkrumah
University of Science
And Technology, Kumasi,
Ghana, Expected in
September 2024

First Class

KINGSLEY BOTCHWAY

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Respectful self-motivator gifted at finding reliable solutions for software issues. Experienced in Backend and Frontend. Offering skills node, express, React, Django, Flask, Sql, Mongodb and Server configuration. Fluent in English and accustomed to working with cross-cultural, global teams.

SKILLS

- Javascript
- Python
- Node
- Dev Ops
- Operating System Power user
- Flask

- Django
- React
- Database
- Software Testing
- Unit Testing
- Problem-Solving

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

October 2023 - Current

Abbeys Software - Desktop Apps, Kumasi

- Coded mysql driven desktop app, using .NET framework and C#
- Designed internal process improvements to automate repetitive tasks, shortening data delivery times.
- Gathered, defined and refined requirements, led project design and oversaw implementation.
- Migrated numerous legacy systems to newer technologies, reducing costs and enhancing efficiency of computing tasks.
- Designed data models for complex analysis needs.

May 2023 - August 2023

Kintampo Coledge Of Health And Well Being - Freelance Web Developer, Kumasi

• Developed online voting systems for their school elections

- Professional
 Development Studies:
 Frontend development,
 2023
- Professional
 Development Studies:
 Backend Development,
 2022
- Electronic Voting, Research Project
- File Storage engine -Research Project

- Multi-tasked across multiple functions and roles to meet deadlines and organizational expectations.
- Designed, implemented and monitored web pages, plugins and functionality for continuous improvement.

October 2022 - December 2022

Our Lady Of Grace Hospital - Web Developer Remote, Kumasi Ghana

- Coded backend for website using Node, Django and Flask
- Coded Frontend websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Bootstrap and other languages languages.
- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, Fetch, and JSON coding.
- · Used git and github for version control
- Engaged with clients to plan and optimize site issues and queries.
- Discussed site and app requirements with clients to produce actionable development plans.

March 2022 - May 2022

Menial Business Associations - Freelancer, Kumasi

- Developed Investment online investment website for their customers to check their investment services online
- Developed and maintained user documentation to establish product understanding.
- Observed packing operations to verify conformance to specifications.

October 2021 - December 2021

Ghana Commercial Bank - Network Administrator and IT Consultant, Breman Asikum

- Developed and implemented policies, procedures, training and development for network resource administration, appropriate use and disaster recovery.
- Recommended and installed upgrades and helped businesses to plan for technology to match growth.
- Implemented and managed operating systems and software, security systems and intrusion detection system

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Software Engineer,

African Leadership Group (ALX), June 2023

Skills: Backend web development, Dev ops, flask, node, express web hosting, linux commands, python, javascript,

C, bash scripting, unit testing, nginx, database, sql, mongodb

<u>verification</u>

https://intranet.alxswe.com/certificates/f5L8CnBHFx

Certified Frontend Web Developer

Meta, November 2023

Skills: front-end web development, react, javascript, version control, principles of ux, html and css, react testing.

<u>verification</u>

https://coursera.org/verify/profession al-cert/4CRWYPK9TWBN

https://www.credly.com/badges/ae395f22-6da5-429a-89fc-d0de1a77d48d/public_url

Certified Backend Developer

Meta, December 2023

Skills: backend developement, Sql databases, django, rest APIs, python, Git and Github, web debugging, unit testing

<u>verification</u>

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/professionalcert/CKBU9DG2EB9Y

https://www.credly.com/badges/36e19b5b-7f9e-4ce5-b4bb-2d391e5104e2/public_url